Shangyi Luo

School of Mechanical Engineering and Automation Harbin Institute of Technology, Shenzhen ≥ lsylsy030516@gmail.com ↑ homepage

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests focus on perception and planning for unmanned vehicle navigation. I hope to improve the ability of robots to infer environmental information and navigate appropriately in complex human-centered environments. Ultimately, my goal is to contribute to the development of mobile robots that can adapt to various open-world scenarios.

EDUCATION _

Harbin Institute of Technology

Sep 2021 - Present

B.E. in Automation (Shenzhen Campus), GPA: 86.331/100

Awards: First-Class Academic Scholarship

Publications _

[1] S. Luo, J. Zhu*, P. Sun*, Y. Deng, C. Yu, A. Xiao, X. Wang, "GSON: A Group-based Social Navigation Framework with Large Multimodal Model", In submission to *International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)*. [Paper] [Video]

EXPERIENCE _

Center for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, Tsinghua SIGS

Jan 2024 – Sep 2024 Shenzhen, China

Research Intern with Prof. Xueqian Wang

- Developed a group-based social navigation framework (GSON) to enable mobile robots to perceive and exploit the social group of their surroundings by leveling the visual reasoning capability of the Large Multimodal Model.
- Applied visual prompting techniques to zero-shot extract the social relationship among pedestrians and combined the result with a robust pedestrian detection and tracking pipeline.
- Proposed a novel planning framework that integrates a social structure-based mid-level planner between global path planning and local motion planning to preserve the global context and reactive response.

Bambu Lab

Jul 2024 – Oct 2024

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Shenzhen, China

- Created a simulation environment of industrial scenes using Blender to support the data generation and testing pipeline for detection algorithm development.
- Applied YOLO and YOLO-world for few-shot, fine-tuning parameters to ensure effective object recognition with limited samples. Explored few-shot learning techniques with transfer learning and data augmentation to improve model accuracy and robustness in industrial applications.

Projects _

RoboMaster Infantry Robot Design and Optimization

Dec 2022 - Dec 2023

Main Contributor, RoboMaster Robotics Competition

- Focused on modular design, including gimbal, chassis, firing module, and wheel assembly, with an emphasis on weight reduction and cost control.
- Leveraged previous designs to upgrade a high-performance infantry robot with excellent firing, movement, and collision resistance capabilities.
- Lead young team members in overcoming technical challenges and accelerating the development of competitive, high-performance robots.

CADC Drone Power System and Payload Design

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

Project Lead, China University Student Aircraft Design Innovation Competition

- Selected optimal power systems, such as motors, propellers, and batteries, based on mission requirements to ensure sufficient thrust and flight endurance.
- Designed an effective payload bay for the safe and accurate transportation and release of specified payloads.
- Conducted iterative flight tests to collect performance data, refining design, and control strategies to improve drone reliability and stability.

SKILLS

- Programming: C++, Python, Matlab, CMake, HTML, Data Structure and Algorithm
- Tools: LaTeX, Pytorch, Git, Linux, OS, Windows
- Interest: Table tennis, Badminton, Running
- Languages: Chinese: Native. English: Advanced (IELTS 7.0)

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE _

• Youth Volunteer Service Organization

April 2022 - April 2023

• Elderly Care Visits

July 2021

• Community Volunteer During Pandemic

Jan~2021